Jagjeet Singh

Male 23 | Gurugram, Haryana, India

☐ +91 856 707 5678 • ☐ iamjagjeetubhi@gmail.com • ☐ https://jagjeet.dev github.com/iamjagjeetubhi • stackoverflow.com/users/4124229/jagjeet-singh

Intro Statement

I'm a Python developer that likes making web applications for the real world.

From the last three years, I was a part of engineering teams, most notably of: GramFactory & Great Developers. Most of the time, I am using Python and Django to create modern web applications and using Celery for asynchronous tasks. The combination of my Python and DevOps skills makes me different from ordinary developers. In the same time, I am sharing my knowledge and helping others on Stack Overflow.

Tech Stack

- **Python 3:** Using Python for work needs from 2016. Has a strong knowledge in Python 3. Knows how to port Python 2 code to Python 3.
- Python web-frameworks: Using Django for building backends for different web applications. And Django Rest Framework for building Web APIs.
- o **JavaScript, CSS, HTML5:** Built first web site in 2012, since actively improving my experience with JavaScript, CSS, and HTML. Have a basic knowledge about React.
- Data Storages: Using PostgreSQL as a data storage for most of the projects & Redis as a cache layer. In same time has a production experience with Memcached.
- o **Infrastructure:** Has a strong feeling, that reliable infrastructure is a must for any modern web application. Knows how to deploy web applications, and how to integrate best dev practices with CI/CD. Deployed applications to Amazon AWS, DigitalOcean and UpCloud.
- Developer Experience: Using git for source management of all my projects. Working between GitHub and BitBucket. Integrating black and flake8 to every possible project via pre-commit hooks. Has confidence in enforcing code style guides for teams to help them perform better and faster.
- Other Tools: Elasticsearch, Celery, Sentry, Jira, Swagger, AWS(EC2, RDS, S3, SNS) and vim.

Experience

Full Stack Developer | DevOps

GramFactory, Gurugram, Haryana, India

Python/ Django 2018–Current

- Software Developer
 - · Created, delivered and maintained scalable system from scratch.
 - · Extended BaseUserManager to use mobile number as username.
 - · Developed OTP module that can be used with any messaging services.
 - · Developed multi-level ERP system.
 - · Developed Product Pricing Module functional upto State, City, Pincode and Shop level.
 - Developed Last Mile Delivery System.
 - · Developed versioned Restful APIs with DRF.
 - Developed Khata Book(Ledger Account Book).

- DevOps

- · Django app deployment using Nginx.
- · Setting up app monitoring with the help of Sentry.
- · Supervisor setup for running multiple Celery Queues.
- · Setting up Let's Encrypt Wildcard Certificate for all QA machines.

Software Engineer Intern

Testing and Consultancy Cell, GNDEC, Ludhiana, Punjab, India

2017-2018

Python/ Django

- Worked on LibreHatti(An ERP system for GNDEC).
 - · Implemented Product Catalogue Module.

· Worked on HTMLtoPDF module for generating Invoices PDF.

Projects

thepoet.me Django based project

https://github.com/iamjagjeetubhi/thepoetdotme

A personal identity page for poets. https://thepoet.me

Mahan Kosh Android based project

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=sikhs.mahankosh Mahan Kosh Application on Play Store is a Punjabi language encyclopedia which

was compiled by Bhai Kahn Singh Nabha over fourteen years.

plzalert.me Django based project

https://github.com/iamjagjeetubhi/plzalertdotme
A notification app for Training and Placement cell, GNDEC https://plzalert.me

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology

Guru Nanak Dev Engineering College, Punjab, India

2014-2018

2018

2018

2017

Achievements

- o First Unicode Sikh encyclopedia with 14k+ downloads.
- o 248K+ views and 188K+ visitors on Wordpress blog across the globe.